[
    {
        "id": "0",
        "question": "What two different ways can scientists can combine elements?",
        "options": [
            "a. Atoms or molecules.",
            "b. Atoms or compounds.",
            "c. Molecules or mixtures.",
            "d. Compounds or mixtures."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Compounds or mixtures."
    },
    {
        "id": "1",
        "question": " In which shell of an atom are the valence electrons located?",
        "options": [
            "a. The outermost.",
            "b. The middle.",
            "c. The second.",
            "d. The first."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The outermost."
    },
    {
        "id": "2",
        "question": "How would you best describes a positive ion?",
        "options": [
            "a. An atom that has an equal number of electrons and protons.",
            "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons.",
            "c. An atom that lost a proton and has more electrons.",
            "d. An atom that cannot throw off any protons."
        ],
        "correct": "b. An atom that lost an electron and has more protons."
    },
    {
        "id": "3",
        "question": "What material permits a large number of free electrons to move through it?",
        "options": [
            "a. Conductor.",
            "b. Insulator.",
            "c. Resistor.",
            "d. Ion."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Conductor."
    },
    {
        "id": "4",
        "question": "Which smallest current can be fatal under certain conditions?",
        "options": [
            "a. One-half of 1 amp",
            "b. One-third of 1 amp.",
            "c. One-tenth of 1 amp.",
            "d. One-eighth of 1 amp."
        ],
        "correct": "c. One-tenth of 1 amp."
    },
    {
        "id": "5",
        "question": "What is used to move a sufficient number of electrons to perform a useful job?",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat.",
            "b. Current.",
            "c. Voltage.",
            "d. Inductance."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Voltage."
    },
    {
        "id": "6",
        "question": "How is resistance defined with respect to electricity?",
        "options": [
            "a. The movement of electrons through a conductor.",
            "b. The opposition to voltage in an electrical circuit.",
            "c. The potential difference offered by a material.",
            "d. The opposition to current flow."
        ],
        "correct": "d. The opposition to current flow."
    },
    {
        "id": "7",
        "question": "According to Ohm's law, how much voltage is needed to push one ampere of current through one ohm of resistance?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.1 volt.",
            "b. 1 volt.",
            "c. 10 volts.",
            "d. 100 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 1 volt."
    },
    {
        "id": "8",
        "question": "What factor normally causes the resistance of a conductor to increase?",
        "options": [
            "a. Decrease in temperature.",
            "b. Increase in temperature.",
            "c. Decrease in length.",
            "d. Increase in size."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Increase in temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": "9",
        "question": "What unit of measurement is used to measure electrical power?",
        "options": [
            "a. Watts.",
            "b. Volts.",
            "c. Amps.",
            "d. Ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question": "How much power does a 3-horsepower motor consumes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.755 kilowatts (kW).",
            "b. 1.534 kW.",
            "c. 2.238 kW.",
            "d. 2.023 kW."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 2.238 kW."
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question": "When do the magnetic lines of force in a magnet cross?",
        "options": [
            "a. When the north pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "b. When the south pole of a magnet is placed near the north pole of another magnet.",
            "c. When a permanent magnet and a temporary magnet are put together.",
            "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic lines of force never cross each other."
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "question": "How can a polarity be created and the strength of the magnetic lines of force around a conductor be increased?",
        "options": [
            "a. By decreasing current.",
            "b. By increasing resistance.",
            "c. By looping coils close together.",
            "d. By increasing the size of the conductor."
        ],
        "correct": "c. By looping coils close together."
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "question": "What methods are the two most common for producing voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Chemical and mechanical.",
            "b. Magnetic and mechanical.",
            "c. Chemical and heat.",
            "d. Magnetic and heat."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Chemical and mechanical."
    },
    {
        "id": "14",
        "question": " What three things are needed to produce voltage by the principle of electromagnetic induction?",
        "options": [
            "a. Coil, core, and current.",
            "b. Magnet, housing, and prime mover.",
            "c. Coil, conductors, and relative motion.",
            "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Magnetic field, a conductor, and relative motion."
    },
    {
        "id": "15",
        "question": "What type of current flow is the result of voltages produced by batteries and thermocouples?",
        "options": [
            "a. Direct current.",
            "b. Alternating current.",
            "c. Easily transformed current.",
            "d. Current of no commercial value."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Direct current."
    },
    {
        "id": "16",
        "question": "Which formula is the correct one for finding the resistance of a circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Current divided by voltage.",
            "b. Voltage divided by current.",
            "c. Current divided by resistance.",
            "d. Voltage divided by resistance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Voltage divided by current."
    },
    {
        "id": "17",
        "question": "How much resistance of a circuit is applied with voltage of 120 volts and a current flow of 9 amperes?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.13 ohms.",
            "b. 1.3 ohms.",
            "c. 13.33 ohms.",
            "d. 108 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 13.33 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "18",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 5-ohm resistor and a 20-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2 ohms.",
            "b. 2.5 ohms.",
            "c. 4 ohms.",
            "d. 5.5 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 4 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "19",
        "question": "What ohm measurement is the total resistance of a 4-ohm resistor, a 10-ohm resistor, and a 12-ohm resistor in parallel?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.3 ohms.",
            "b. 3.2 ohms.",
            "c. 3.9 ohms.",
            "d. 4.2 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.3 ohms."
    },
    {
        "id": "20",
        "question": " What measurement is the current flow in amperes of a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a power consumption of 600 watts?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.5 amperes.",
            "b. 2 amperes.",
            "c. 2.5 amperes.",
            "d. 5 amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5 amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "21",
        "question": "What amount of power in watts is consumed by a circuit with 120 volts applied and a resistance of 12 ohms?",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 watts.",
            "b. 12 watts.",
            "c. 1200 watts.",
            "d. 1440 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 1200 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "22",
        "question": " How many watts of power are present in a 5-ohm unit of resistance in which 2 amperes are flowing?",
        "options": [
            "a. 20 watts.",
            "b. 15 watts.",
            "c. 10 watts.",
            "d. 2.5 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 20 watts."
    },
    {
        "id": "23",
        "question": "What completes an electrical cycle of an alternating current (AC) generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. One positive and two negative alternations in one second.",
            "b. One positive and one negative alternation.",
            "c. One negative alternation.",
            "d. One positive alternation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. One positive and one negative alternation."
    },
    {
        "id": "24",
        "question": "How many rotations per minute (rpm) must a two-pole generator rotate to produce 60 hertz",
        "options": [
            "a. 1,200 rpm.",
            "b. 1,800 rpm.",
            "c. 3,600 rpm.",
            "d. 4,000 rpm."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3,600 rpm."
    },
    {
        "id": "25",
        "question": "How is the measurement of the apparent power of an alternating current (AC) electrical system expressed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Volt-amperes.",
            "b. Kilovolt-amperes.",
            "c. Millivolt-amperes.",
            "d. Picovolt-amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Kilovolt-amperes."
    },
    {
        "id": "26",
        "question": "What is the capacitance of a 125 microfarads (Î¼F) capacitor when converted to farads?",
        "options": [
            "a. .000125 F.",
            "b. .00125 F.",
            "c. .0125 F.",
            "d. 0.125 F."
        ],
        "correct": "a. .000125 F."
    },
    {
        "id": "27",
        "question": "The rules and equations for direct current (DC) circuits apply to alternating current (AC) circuits having",
        "options": [
            "a. resistive load elements alone.",
            "b. reactive load elements alone.",
            "c. capacitive load elements alone.",
            "d. resistive and reactive load elements."
        ],
        "correct": "a. resistive load elements alone."
    },
    {
        "id": "28",
        "question": "A 110-volt alternating current (AC) motor records 20 in-line amperes and the in-line wattmeter shows only 1,936 watts being consumed. What would be the power factor of the AC circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. 80 percent power factor (pf).",
            "b. 83 percent pf.",
            "c. 86 percent pf.",
            "d. 88 percent pf."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 88 percent pf."
    },
    {
        "id": "29",
        "question": "What is the purpose of an electrical generator?",
        "options": [
            "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy.",
            "b. Converts electrical energy to mechanical energy.",
            "c. Converts kinetic energy to electrical energy.",
            "d. Converts kinetic energy to potential energy."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Converts mechanical energy to electrical energy."
    },
    {
        "id": "30",
        "question": "What type of generator has brushes riding on the commutator to carry the current to an external circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. Universal.",
            "b. Potential type.",
            "c. Direct current type.",
            "d. Alternating current type."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Direct current type."
    },
    {
        "id": "31",
        "question": "What feature is the advantage of having a rotating magnetic field alternator?",
        "options": [
            "a. It requires no slip rings and brushes.",
            "b. Output is taken from the commutator.",
            "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils.",
            "d. It requires less power to rotate the magnetic field."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Output is taken from the stationary stator coils."
    },
    {
        "id": "32",
        "question": "The voltage of a primary cell depends on the type of",
        "options": [
            "a. electrolyte and type of cell.",
            "b. cell and type of terminal posts.",
            "c. electrode material and type of cell.",
            "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
        ],
        "correct": "d. electrolyte and the electrode material."
    },
    {
        "id": "33",
        "question": "Even though the open-circuit voltage of a lead-acid storage battery is approximately 2.2 volts, what number is the normal rating?",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.0.",
            "b. 2.5.",
            "c. 2.7.",
            "d. 2.9."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2.0."
    },
    {
        "id": "34",
        "question": "A step-up transformer produces a secondary voltage",
        "options": [
            "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary. ",
            "b. lower and secondary current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "c. and current higher than the voltage and current in the primary.",
            "d. and current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
        ],
        "correct": "a. higher and secondary current lower than the voltage and current in the primary."
    },
    {
        "id": "35",
        "question": "When setting up the bucket truck for rescue, where should you place the strap and how far from the bucket?",
        "options": [
            "a. Lower boom; 10 feet.",
            "b. Lower boom; 15 feet.",
            "c. Upper boom; 10 feet.",
            "d. Upper boom; 15 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Upper boom; 10 feet."
    },
    {
        "id": "36",
        "question": "What two items do you need when setting up the bucket truck for rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline and a set of rope blocks.",
            "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks.",
            "c. Hot stick and handline.",
            "d. Strap and hot stick."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Strap and a set of rope blocks."
    },
    {
        "id": "37",
        "question": " Which piece of equipment should you use with the manhole guard when using the two-person method of manhole rescue?",
        "options": [
            "a. Handline.",
            "b. Wire hoist.",
            "c. Rope blocks.",
            "d. Windlass handcrank."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Windlass handcrank."
    },
    {
        "id": "38",
        "question": "When rescuing a person from a manhole, your primary concern should be",
        "options": [
            "a. your own safety.",
            "b. the speed of the rescue.",
            "c. the depth of the manhole.",
            "d. not to cause additional injuries."
        ],
        "correct": "a. your own safety."
    },
    {
        "id": "39",
        "question": "What action should you always take when using a two-way radio for line work?",
        "options": [
            "a. Get clearances from the shop",
            "b. Know where other crews are working.",
            "c. Identify yourself on each transmission.",
            "d. Use the electrical shop code on each transmission."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Identify yourself on each transmission."
    },
    {
        "id": "40",
        "question": "Who is responsible for issuing a safe clearance?",
        "options": [
            "a. Craftsman.",
            "b. Crew leader.",
            "c. Superintendent.",
            "d. Base civil engineer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Superintendent."
    },
    {
        "id": "41",
        "question": "How many year(s) must safe clearance forms be retained after release?",
        "options": [
            "a. Four.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Two.",
            "d. One."
        ],
        "correct": "d. One."
    },
    {
        "id": "42",
        "question": "Which Air Force (AF) form is used to record all blocking and tagging actions done on primary electrical circuits on Air Force installations?",
        "options": [
            "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance.",
            "b. AF Form 561, BCE Weekly Work Schedule.",
            "c. AF Form 979, Danger Tag.",
            "d. AF Form 980, Caution Tag."
        ],
        "correct": "a. AF Form 269, Electrical Facilities Safe Clearance."
    },
    {
        "id": "43",
        "question": "Why do you use the Air Force (AF) Form 980, Caution Tag?",
        "options": [
            "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary.",
            "b. To control and record all blocking and tagging.",
            "c. To protect the crew working under safe clearance.",
            "d. To record the names of the crew that are doing the task."
        ],
        "correct": "a. To identify situations out of the ordinary."
    },
    {
        "id": "44",
        "question": "At which of the following voltages can you work from the structure using rubber gloves?",
        "options": [
            "a. 24,900 volts and below.",
            "b. 13,800 volts and below.",
            "c. 13,200 volts and below.",
            "d. 4,160 volts and below."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 4,160 volts and below."
    },
    {
        "id": "45",
        "question": "Which safety briefing point is not covered during a tailgate meeting? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Special practices or grounding requirements.",
            "b. Certification of live line maintenance.",
            "c. Description of the work to be done.",
            "d. Identification of the work site."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Certification of live line maintenance."
    },
    {
        "id": "46",
        "question": "What document is used to record system problems, such as outages, surges, or low voltages?",
        "options": [
            "a. Power outage log.",
            "b. Special procedure log.",
            "c. Emergency maintenance record",
            "d. Emergency operations checklist."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Power outage log."
    },
    {
        "id": "47",
        "question": " What records are kept to make sure proper maintenance and repair are done on the electrical distribution system?",
        "options": [
            "a. Equipment records only.",
            "b. Maintenance records only.",
            "c. Equipment and maintenance records.",
            "d. Equipment, maintenance, and computer data records."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Equipment and maintenance records."
    },
    {
        "id": "48",
        "question": "Which of the following is not required to establish a proper maintenance program?",
        "options": [
            "a. Knowing the scope of work.",
            "b. Establishing methods of application.",
            "c. Establishing intervals of performance.",
            "d. Having adequate and dependable supply of power."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Having adequate and dependable supply of power."
    },
    {
        "id": "49",
        "question": "Which instrument gives immediate qualitative information on the degree and type of distortion?",
        "options": [
            "a. Oscilloscope.",
            "b. Wave analyzer.",
            "c. Frequency meter.",
            "d. Spectrum analyzer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Oscilloscope."
    },
    {
        "id": "50",
        "question": " What frequencies, in hertz (Hz), are the most common for transmission of electrical power?",
        "options": [
            "a. 50, 60, 5.",
            "b. 25, 50, 60.",
            "c. 25, 50, 400.",
            "d. 50, 60, 400."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 50, 60, 400."
    },
    {
        "id": "51",
        "question": "The output voltage of the electronic voltage regulator circuit",
        "options": [
            "a. cannot be adjusted to a specific value.",
            "b. can be adjusted to a specific value.",
            "c. is adjusted by the manufacturer.",
            "d. is adjusted automatically."
        ],
        "correct": "b. can be adjusted to a specific value."
    },
    {
        "id": "52",
        "question": "What purpose does the zener diode in the electronic voltage regulator serve?",
        "options": [
            "a. Acts as a biasing source.",
            "b. Regulates output voltage.",
            "c. Sets the reference voltage.",
            "d. Provides transistor reverse bias."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Sets the reference voltage."
    },
    {
        "id": "53",
        "question": "Input resistance to a common collector amplifier is high because the emitter signal opposes the",
        "options": [
            "a. base signal.",
            "b. base resistance.",
            "c. collector signal.",
            "d. output resistance."
        ],
        "correct": "a. base signal."
    },
    {
        "id": "54",
        "question": "The process of returning a part of the output of an amplifier back to its input in such a manner that it cancels part of the input signal is known as",
        "options": [
            "a. degeneration.",
            "b. signal cancellation.",
            "c. high-input impedance.",
            "d. regenerative feedback."
        ],
        "correct": "a. degeneration."
    },
    {
        "id": "55",
        "question": "Which gain characteristics of a common base transistor amplifier is less than one?",
        "options": [
            "a. Impedance.",
            "b. Voltage.",
            "c. Current.",
            "d. Power."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Current."
    },
    {
        "id": "56",
        "question": "The controlling element in a common base configuration is the",
        "options": [
            "a. emitter.",
            "b. collector.",
            "c. emitter base.",
            "d. collector base."
        ],
        "correct": "a. emitter."
    },
    {
        "id": "57",
        "question": " What does the positive alternation of an input signal to the base of an NPN transistor in a common emitter configuration cause?",
        "options": [
            "a. An increase in collector current.",
            "b. A decrease in collector current.",
            "c. An increase in base current.",
            "d. A decrease in base current."
        ],
        "correct": "c. An increase in base current."
    },
    {
        "id": "58",
        "question": "In the common emitter configuration, the input is between the emitter and base and the output is between the",
        "options": [
            "a. base and collector.",
            "b. base and common.",
            "c. emitter and common.",
            "d. collector and emitter."
        ],
        "correct": "d. collector and emitter."
    },
    {
        "id": "59",
        "question": "What does the word electronics mean?",
        "options": [
            "a. Vacuum.",
            "b. Optimum current flow.",
            "c. Precise voltage regulation.",
            "d. Applications involving the control of electricity."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Applications involving the control of electricity."
    },
    {
        "id": "60",
        "question": "An electron is considered a free electron when it reaches the",
        "options": [
            "a. nucleus.",
            "b. valence band.",
            "c. forbidden level.",
            "d. conduction band."
        ],
        "correct": "d. conduction band."
    },
    {
        "id": "61",
        "question": "A positive mobile charge is considered",
        "options": [
            "a. hole.",
            "b. valence.",
            "c. nucleus.",
            "d. rectifier."
        ],
        "correct": "a. hole."
    },
    {
        "id": "62",
        "question": "Excessive external heat applied to electronic components",
        "options": [
            "a. has no adverse effects.",
            "b. causes increased current flow.",
            "c. causes decreased current flow.",
            "d. improves operation of components."
        ],
        "correct": "b. causes increased current flow."
    },
    {
        "id": "63",
        "question": "Which device should only be used in direct current (DC) circuits?",
        "options": [
            "a. Electrolytic capacitors.",
            "b. Capacitors.",
            "c. Resistors.",
            "d. Diodes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Electrolytic capacitors."
    },
    {
        "id": "64",
        "question": "Which of the following is another term for a diode? ",
        "options": [
            "a. PN junction.",
            "b. PN resistor.",
            "c. Amplifier.",
            "d. Triac."
        ],
        "correct": "a. PN junction."
    },
    {
        "id": "65",
        "question": " Which multimeter lead connection is used to read forward bias on a diode?",
        "options": [
            "a. Polarity does not matter.",
            "b. Black to cathode.",
            "c. Black to anode.",
            "d. Red to cathode."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Black to cathode."
    },
    {
        "id": "66",
        "question": "What does the arrow in semiconductors indicate?",
        "options": [
            "a. The direction of minority current receivers.",
            "b. The direction of majority current carriers.",
            "c. The direction of electron flow.",
            "d. The direction of hole current."
        ],
        "correct": "d. The direction of hole current."
    },
    {
        "id": "67",
        "question": "What does a flat side or shorter lead on some light emitting diodes indicate?",
        "options": [
            "a. Low voltage side.",
            "b. Anode.",
            "c. Junction.",
            "d. Cathode."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Cathode."
    },
    {
        "id": "68",
        "question": "What is a zener diode typically used for?",
        "options": [
            "a. Current negation.",
            "b. Current oscillation.",
            "c. Voltage regulation.",
            "d. Voltage amplification."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "69",
        "question": "How are the electrode leads identified and labeled on a Bipolar Junction Transistor?",
        "options": [
            "a. Positive and negative.",
            "b. Anode and cathode.",
            "c. Emitter, base, and collector.",
            "d. Anode, cathode, and gate."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Emitter, base, and collector."
    },
    {
        "id": "70",
        "question": "Which letter combinations are types of Bipolar Junction Transistors?",
        "options": [
            "a. PNPN, NPNP.",
            "b. NNPP, PPNN.",
            "c. PNN, NPP.",
            "d. NPN, PNP."
        ],
        "correct": "d. NPN, PNP."
    },
    {
        "id": "71",
        "question": "How many layers of semiconducting material does a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) have?",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Four."
    },
    {
        "id": "72",
        "question": "How is the emitter base junction on a transistor connected?",
        "options": [
            "a. Forward biased.",
            "b. Reverse biased.",
            "c. Front biased.",
            "d. Rear biased."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Forward biased."
    },
    {
        "id": "73",
        "question": "How does the base of a transistor normally receive its control voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Multiplexor circuit.",
            "b. Voltage divider circuit.",
            "c. Independent battery circuit.",
            "d. Separately derived power source."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Voltage divider circuit."
    },
    {
        "id": "74",
        "question": "Transistors can be connected in how many configurations?",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Six."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Three."
    },
    {
        "id": "75",
        "question": "What controls the conduction time of a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR)?",
        "options": [
            "a. A decrease in forward bias.",
            "b. A decrease in reverse bias.",
            "c. Anode current.",
            "d. Gate current."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Gate current."
    },
    {
        "id": "76",
        "question": "How do you turn off a silicon controlled rectifier (SCR) in a minimum amount of time?",
        "options": [
            "a. Apply reverse bias to the gate.",
            "b. Apply forward bias to the gate.",
            "c. Apply reverse bias to the anode.",
            "d. Apply forward bias to the anode."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Apply reverse bias to the anode."
    },
    {
        "id": "77",
        "question": "Information showing the location of installed distribution equipment should be kept",
        "options": [
            "a. on the maintenance truck.",
            "b. on a distribution map in the shop.",
            "c. in the distribution substation house.",
            "d. in the base civil engineer's (BCE) office."
        ],
        "correct": "b. on a distribution map in the shop."
    },
    {
        "id": "78",
        "question": "What is developed for logic gate circuits to determine signal output?",
        "options": [
            "a. Truth tables.",
            "b. Sizing charts.",
            "c. Component values.",
            "d. Operating thresholds."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Truth tables."
    },
    {
        "id": "79",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a logic gate?",
        "options": [
            "a. NAND.",
            "b. STOP.",
            "c. NOR.",
            "d. OR."
        ],
        "correct": "b. STOP."
    },
    {
        "id": "80",
        "question": "The two purposes of the load resistor of a half-wave rectifier is to develop the output signal and to",
        "options": [
            "a. provide reverse bias.",
            "b. determine output amplitude.",
            "c. limit current flow to a safe level.",
            "d. limit output voltage to a safe level."
        ],
        "correct": "c. limit current flow to a safe level."
    },
    {
        "id": "81",
        "question": "If the input frequency to a half-wave rectifier is 120 Hz, its output ripple frequency is",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 hertz (Hz).",
            "b. 240 Hz.",
            "c. 60 pulses per second (pps).",
            "d. 120 pps."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 120 pps."
    },
    {
        "id": "82",
        "question": "A full-wave rectifier can be identified easily on a schematic because it contains",
        "options": [
            "a. three diodes.",
            "b. a center-tapped transformer.",
            "c. two diodes with a cross resistor.",
            "d. a side transformer and four diodes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. a center-tapped transformer."
    },
    {
        "id": "83",
        "question": "The breakdown rating for diodes in a full-wave rectifier must be twice as great as the",
        "options": [
            "a. breakdown rating of one diode.",
            "b. half-wave rectifier diode.",
            "c. average output voltage.",
            "d. size of the load."
        ],
        "correct": "b. half-wave rectifier diode."
    },
    {
        "id": "84",
        "question": "What frequency is the output ripple of a bridge rectifier with an input frequency of 60 hertz (Hz)?",
        "options": [
            "a. 60 Hz.",
            "b. 60 pulses per second (pps).",
            "c. 120 pps.",
            "d. 120 Hz."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 120 pps."
    },
    {
        "id": "85",
        "question": "The output ripple frequency of a three-phase bridge rectifier is how many times the input frequency?",
        "options": [
            "a. Three times.",
            "b. Four times.",
            "c. Five times.",
            "d. Six times."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Six times."
    },
    {
        "id": "86",
        "question": "During pole-top rescue, the rope should be ",
        "options": [
            "a. tied through the back of the victim's body belt.",
            "b. tied through the front of the victim's body belt.",
            "c. passed through the crossarm braces and over the crossarm.",
            "d. passed around the victim's chest and tied with three half hitches."
        ],
        "correct": "d. passed around the victim's chest and tied with three half hitches."
    },
    {
        "id": "87",
        "question": "When testing the oxygen level of a confined space, the oxygen level should be within what percentage (%)?",
        "options": [
            "a. 18-20.",
            "b. 15-22.",
            "c. 19.5-23.5",
            "d. 18.5-22.5."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 19.5-23.5"
    },
    {
        "id": "88",
        "question": "Why does a ripple voltage exist in a circuit powered by a rectifier? ",
        "options": [
            "a. The rectifier supplies energy to the load in pulses.",
            "b. A characteristic of the rectifier is to store energy.",
            "c. Rectifiers supply a smooth voltage to the load.",
            "d. It is a characteristic of alternating current."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The rectifier supplies energy to the load in pulses."
    },
    {
        "id": "89",
        "question": "The bowline knot is placed in front of a victim in the two-person method of manhole rescue to",
        "options": [
            "The bowline knot is placed in front of a victim in the two-person method of manhole rescue to",
            "b. prevent the knot from slipping.",
            "c. prevent the victim's head from hitting the side of the manhole.",
            "d. allow the victim's head to tilt back, keeping the victim's air passage open."
        ],
        "correct": "d. allow the victim's head to tilt back, keeping the victim's air passage open."
    },
    {
        "id": "90",
        "question": "An inductive (choke) input filter gives a lower output voltage than the capacitive input LC filter and also",
        "options": [
            "a. inductive regulation.",
            "b. high-output impedance.",
            "c. poor voltage regulation.",
            "d. better voltage regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "d. better voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "91",
        "question": "Which of these characteristics are one of the pi-type LC filter?",
        "options": [
            "a. Low-input voltage and no voltage regulation.",
            "b. High-input voltage and no voltage regulation.",
            "c. Low-output voltage and better voltage regulation.",
            "d. High-output voltage and better voltage regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "d. High-output voltage and better voltage regulation."
    },
    {
        "id": "92",
        "question": "Which condition exists when you connect the negative battery lead to a cathode?",
        "options": [
            "a. Frontal bias.",
            "b. Neutral bias.",
            "c. Reverse bias.",
            "d. Forward bias."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Forward bias."
    },
    {
        "id": "93",
        "question": "The output of a three-phase bridge rectifier is of low amplitude and requires",
        "options": [
            "a. very little filtering.",
            "b. to be stepped up.",
            "c. heavy filtering.",
            "d. no filtering."
        ],
        "correct": "a. very little filtering."
    },
    {
        "id": "94",
        "question": "What type of current flow cannot be transformed from a higher voltage to a lower voltage?",
        "options": [
            "a. Alternating current.",
            "b. Direct current.",
            "c. Low current.",
            "d. Electric."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Direct current."
    },
    {
        "id": "95",
        "question": "How much current flow is in a circuit with 24 volts applied and with 72-ohms resistance?",
        "options": [
            "a. 0.33 amperes.",
            "b. 3.3 amperes.",
            "c. 33.0 amperes.",
            "d. 0.728 amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 0.33 amperes."
    },
    {
        "question": "1. (201) Which section of the Operation and Service Instructions Manual contains instructions for uncrating, installing, and preparing equipment for initial operations?",
        "options": [
            "a. Section 1.",
            "b. Section 2.",
            "c. Section 3.",
            "d. Section 4."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Section 3."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (201) Which section of the Operation and Service Instructions Manual contains step-by-step instructions for starting, operating, and stopping equipment?",
        "options": [
            "a. Section 1.",
            "b. Section 2.",
            "c. Section 3.",
            "d. Section 4."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Section 4."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (202) Which time compliance technical order (TCTO) requires you to discontinue use of equipment until prescribed maintenance work is completed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Interim TCTOs.",
            "b. Record TCTOs.",
            "c. Urgent action TCTOs.",
            "d. Immediate action TCTOs."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Immediate action TCTOs."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (202) The time compliance technical order (TCTO) that must be issued if the risk involved is tolerable only within definite time limits is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. record TCTO.",
            "b. interim TCTO.",
            "c. urgent action TCTO.",
            "d. immediate action TCTO."
        ],
        "correct": "c. urgent action TCTO."
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (203) What do all technical order (TO) indexes have as the first number? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Zero (0).",
            "b. One (1).",
            "c. Two (2).",
            "d. Three (3)."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Zero (0)."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (204) What format is used to submit corrections to a technical order (TO)?",
        "options": [
            "a. TO 00-5-1, AF Technical Order System.",
            "b. TO 0-1-01, Numerical Index and Requirements Tables.",
            "c. AFTO Form 158, Technical Order Review Comment Sheet.",
            "d. AFTO Form 22, Technical Manual (TM) Change Recommendation and Reply."
        ],
        "correct": "d. AFTO Form 22, Technical Manual (TM) Change Recommendation and Reply."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (204) Which technical order (TO) improvement recommendation requires action within 40 days of its receipt?",
        "options": [
            "a. Urgent.",
            "b. Routine.",
            "c. Time compliance.",
            "d. Emergency/critical hazard."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Urgent."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (204) What type of technical order (TO) improvement recommendation is submitted if prescribed maintenance procedures reduce the operational life of equipment?",
        "options": [
            "a. Urgent.",
            "b. Routine.",
            "c. Emergency.",
            "d. Time compliance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Routine."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (205) How are Unified Criteria Facilities (UFC) organized?",
        "options": [
            "a. Units and Volumes.",
            "b. Chapters and Articles.",
            "c. Chapters and Volumes.",
            "d. Series and Sub-Categories."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Series and Sub-Categories."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (205) What information is in Chapter 1 of a Unified Criteria Facilities (UFC)?",
        "options": [
            "a. General overview listing the purpose, scope, and references for the UFC.",
            "b. Table of contents.",
            "c. Foreword.",
            "d. Glossary."
        ],
        "correct": "a. General overview listing the purpose, scope, and references for the UFC."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (206) Who publishes the National Electric Code? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA).",
            "b. American National Standards Institute (ANSI).",
            "c. National Electrical Manufactures Association (NEMA).",
            "d. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA)."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (206) What publication number is the National Electric Code?",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E.",
            "b. NFPA 72.",
            "c. NFPA 70B.",
            "d. NFPA 70."
        ],
        "correct": "d. NFPA 70."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (206) What publication number is the Standard for Electrical Safety in the Workplace? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E.",
            "b. NFPA 72.",
            "c. NFPA 70B.",
            "d. NFPA 70."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (207) What number is the maximum ohmic reading for static grounds according to current Air Force directives? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10.",
            "b. 1,000.",
            "c. 10,000.",
            "d. 100,000."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 10,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (207) An equipment ground is a grounding system that ",
        "options": [
            "a. stabilizes voltage between two or more metallic objects.",
            "b. removes excess voltage from current carrying metallic objects.",
            "c. drains off static electricity before a sparking potential is reached.",
            "d. connects to earth all nonconcurrent carrying metal parts of an electrical wiring system."
        ],
        "correct": "d. connects to earth all nonconcurrent carrying metal parts of an electrical wiring system."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (207) What maximum ground resistance is the value for an electrical system with a voltage of 600 volts alternating current (VAC) or less?",
        "options": [
            "a. 1 ohm.",
            "b. 5 ohms.",
            "c. 10 ohms.",
            "d. 25 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 25 ohms."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (207) During which season could you expect to measure the lowest ground reading? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Fall.",
            "b. Spring.",
            "c. Summer.",
            "d. Winter."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Spring."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (208) Which location is the correct location for grounding a system neutral? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Load side of service entrance.",
            "b. Source side of service entrance.",
            "c. Load side of service entrance and outlets.",
            "d. Source side of service entrance and outlets."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Source side of service entrance."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (208) A system neutral conductor is likely grounded improperly (grounded on the load side of the service entrance disconnect), if the ohmic value is less than ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10K.",
            "b. 20K.",
            "c. 30K.",
            "d. 40K."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 20K."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (209) At what intervals should a wye-connected distribution system neutral be grounded? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At a distance not to exceed Â¼ mile.",
            "b. At a distance not to exceed Â½ mile.",
            "c. At a distance not to exceed 1 mile.",
            "d. This system neutral is not grounded."
        ],
        "correct": "a. At a distance not to exceed Â¼ mile."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (209) What recommended depth is the top of a ground rod driven for distribution pole grounding? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At ground level.",
            "b. Below ground level.",
            "c. 1 foot above ground level.",
            "d. 2 feet below ground level."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 2 feet below ground level."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (210) The metal frame of a building can be used as a facility ground ",
        "options": [
            "a. if the frame is effectively grounded.",
            "b. if the building is equipped with air terminals.",
            "c. only when it is supported by insulated flanges.",
            "d. only if the braces are separately bonded to the ground loop."
        ],
        "correct": "a. if the frame is effectively grounded."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (210) What are the requirements for a facility ground rod? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 4 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or galvanized steel.",
            "b. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or galvanized steel.",
            "c. 4 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel.",
            "d. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (210) Which is the minimum allowed resistance for an electrode used for communications network grounds? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25 ohms.",
            "b. 20 ohms.",
            "c. 10 ohms.",
            "d. 5 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 10 ohms."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (210) Isolated ground (IG) receptacles are used in circuits feeding electronic devices to ",
        "options": [
            "a. minimize noise.",
            "b. filter voltage spikes.",
            "c. stabilize current draw.",
            "d. block high voltage generated from lightning strikes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. minimize noise."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (210) In an isolated ground (IG) receptacle, the ",
        "options": [
            "a. grounding pin is purposely insulated from the outlet box.",
            "b. IG will be bonded to other grounds in the immediate area.",
            "c. IG must have its own lightning arrester.",
            "d. IG must have its own driven ground rod."
        ],
        "correct": "a. grounding pin is purposely insulated from the outlet box."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (211) What happens if a bare grounding wire touches the hot conductor terminal of a receptacle inside of a properly grounded outlet box? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Equipment plugged in the receptacle receives excessive current and overheats.",
            "b. The neutrals for the entire facility become hot conductors.",
            "c. The circuit breaker for that circuit trips.",
            "d. The outlet voltage is doubled."
        ],
        "correct": "c. The circuit breaker for that circuit trips."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (211) Physical failure of grounding systems usually occurs in which portion of the system? ",
        "options": [
            "a. In the service panel.",
            "b. The ground electrode.",
            "c. Just above and below ground level.",
            "d. At the point where it attaches to the equipment."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Just above and below ground level."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (211) In an interior wiring system with metallic conduit, through how many possible paths can return ground fault flow?",
        "options": [
            "a. Zero.",
            "b. One.",
            "c. Two.",
            "d. Three."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Two."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (211) What test can you perform to ensure that the above grade components in a grounding system have a low resistance path to ground? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Earth resistance test.",
            "b. Vibroground test.",
            "c. Continuity test.",
            "d. Clamp-on test."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Continuity test."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (212) What characteristics are the properties of good insulators?",
        "options": [
            "a. Clean dry surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "b. Clean dry surfaces in high humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "c. Contaminated surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "d. Clean dry surfaces in any humidity; permit leakage to take place."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Clean dry surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (212) What minimum sparking voltage is generally accepted for the shortest measurable length of gap?",
        "options": [
            "a. 12 volts.",
            "b. 125 volts.",
            "c. 240 volts.",
            "d. 350 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 350 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (213) Under proper conditions, approximately how much voltage can be charged up by a drop of liquid falling through the air? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 50 volts.",
            "b. 500 volts.",
            "c. 1,000 volts.",
            "d. 10,000 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 10,000 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (213) At what voltage can a static charge ignite gasoline? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 volts.",
            "b. 750 volts.",
            "c. 1,500 volts.",
            "d. 7,500 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 1,500 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (213) Unwanted electrical charges in hazardous areas are dissipated by using ",
        "options": [
            "a. rubber mats.",
            "b. air filtration systems.",
            "c. a continuous electrical path to ground.",
            "d. static elimination bars at all entry points."
        ],
        "correct": "c. a continuous electrical path to ground."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (213) Which is not necessary for an adequate ground for static electricity? ",
        "options": [
            "a. High mechanical strength.",
            "b. Very low resistance.",
            "c. Secure connections.",
            "d. A continuous path."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Very low resistance."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (213) Which size copper wire is used to bond conductive objects when they are not concealed or mechanically protected? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 16 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. No. 12 AWG.",
            "c. No. 8 AWG.",
            "d. No. 6 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "d. No. 6 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (214) The type of ionic current that describes the rate of electron loss from earth is called ",
        "options": [
            "a. air-earth.",
            "b. air-water.",
            "c. sky-earth.",
            "d. sky-water."
        ],
        "correct": "a. air-earth."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (214) The process of separating air molecules into positive ions and negative electrons is called ",
        "options": [
            "a. ionization.",
            "b. salinization.",
            "c. de-ionization.",
            "d. de-salinization."
        ],
        "correct": "a. ionization."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (215) Lightning grounds are designed ",
        "options": [
            "a. to handle high voltages.",
            "b. to carry large currents.",
            "c. for high capacitance.",
            "d. for high impedance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. to carry large currents."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (215) What size is the minimum for grounding conductors used for hazardous locations? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 6 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. No. 4 AWG.",
            "c. No. 1/0 AWG.",
            "d. No. 4/0 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "c. No. 1/0 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (215) The maximum spacing, in feet, between air terminals is ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 100.",
            "d. 150."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 25."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (215) What number of inches is the minimum radius for lightning protection conductors bend? ",
        "options": [
            "a. One.",
            "b. Two.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Eight."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Eight."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (216) Grounding of lightning protection systems should conform to ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 77.",
            "b. NFPA 78.",
            "c. NFPA 780.",
            "d. NFPA 802."
        ],
        "correct": "c. NFPA 780."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (216) What size ground rods are used in a lightning protection system? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 8 feet in length, and 1/2-inch diameter.",
            "b. 8 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter.",
            "c. 10 feet in length, and 1/2-inch diameter.",
            "d. 10 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 10 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. (216) When ground rods are used with a loop conductor, how deep are ground rod tops driven?",
        "options": [
            "a. 6 inches below finished grade.",
            "b. 18 inches below finished grade.",
            "c. To same elevation as loop conductor below finished grade.",
            "d. To same elevation as the facility ground below finished grade."
        ],
        "correct": "c. To same elevation as loop conductor below finished grade."
    },
    {
        "question": "47. (216) What is the minimum size copper wire used to connect different grounding systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 14 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. 6 AWG.",
            "c. 2 AWG.",
            "d. 1/0 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 6 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "48. (217) What number of feet must down conductors not exceed? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 100.",
            "d. 125."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 100."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. (217) How far into the ground must grounding rings be buried? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 inches.",
            "b. 15 inches.",
            "c. 30 inches.",
            "d. 45 inches."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 30 inches."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. (218) The ions that leave the metal and enter into the solution are ",
        "options": [
            "a. free electrons.",
            "b. anodes.",
            "c. positive.",
            "d. negative."
        ],
        "correct": "b. anodes."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. (219) How many basic ways can corrosion occur? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Four."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. (219) Where does stray current corrosion cause greatest damage? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At midpoint between entry and exit of a structure. b. The bottom side of a structure.",
            "c. Where it enters a structure.",
            "d. Where it exits a structure."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Where it exits a structure."
    },
    {
        "question": "53. (220) How many ways can cathodic protection be achieved? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.",
            "b. 4.",
            "c. 6.",
            "d. 8."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (220) At least how many inches of backfill should extend from each end of the anode? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 4.",
            "b. 8.",
            "c. 10.",
            "d. 12."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 12."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (221) What purpose does the rectifier operational inspection serve?",
        "options": [
            "a. To determine the serviceability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "b. To determine the unserviceability of some components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "c. To determine the reliability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "d. To determine the compatibility of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system."
        ],
        "correct": "a. To determine the serviceability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. (221) How often should a structure be checked for depth of pitting?",
        "options": [
            "a. Every two years.",
            "b. Yearly.",
            "c. Semiannually.",
            "d. Monthly."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Every two years."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. (222) What voltage does a fire alarm system operate on, and what additional power source does the panel have? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 12 volts, direct current (VDC),backup circuit.",
            "b. 12VDC, battery backup.",
            "c. 24VDC, backup circuit.",
            "d. 24VDC, battery backup."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 24VDC, battery backup."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. (222) What is defined as a situation, environmental state, or equipment state of a fire alarm? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Alarm.",
            "b. Condition.",
            "c. Trouble.",
            "d. Situation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Condition."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. (222) What situation would cause the fire department dispatch center to receive a supervisory alarm? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Open in a circuit.",
            "b. Ground on a circuit.",
            "c. Initiating device operates.",
            "d. Someone disables the fire suppression system."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Someone disables the fire suppression system."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. (223) Where in a facility will a pull station be located? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Next to fire alarm control panel.",
            "b. Near exits and in exit stairwells.",
            "c. Mechanical room.",
            "d. In every room."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Near exits and in exit stairwells."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. (223) What type of automatic detector is susceptible to false alarms in dusty environments? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat detector.",
            "b. Ion Smoke detector.",
            "c. Wavelength detector.",
            "d. Photoelectric Smoke detector."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Photoelectric Smoke detector."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. (223) What monitors the air in a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) system for signs of fire? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat detector.",
            "b. Flow detector.",
            "c. Duct detector.",
            "d. Smoke detector."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Duct detector."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. (223) Where is the end of line resistor in a Class A circuit? ",
        "options": [
            "a. In the middle of the circuit.",
            "b. At the end of the circuit.",
            "c. In the panel.",
            "d. Not used."
        ],
        "correct": "c. In the panel."
    },
    {
        "question": "64. (223) What is used in larger facilities to expand the notification appliance circuit (NAC)? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Initiating device circuit extender.",
            "b. Power amplifier.",
            "c. Booster panel.",
            "d. Amp panel."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Booster panel."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. (223) What is the polarity of a notification appliance circuit (NAC) that has been activated?",
        "options": [
            "a. Forward.",
            "b. Reverse.",
            "c. Alternating.",
            "d. None of the above."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Reverse."
    },
    {
        "question": "66. (224) How is an addressable circuit supervised? ",
        "options": [
            "a. The detectors \"Talk\" to the fire alarm control panel (FACP).",
            "b. The FACP broadcasts messages to all the detectors.",
            "c. The detectors relay messages to the FACP.",
            "d. The same as in a conventional system"
        ],
        "correct": "a. The detectors \"Talk\" to the fire alarm control panel (FACP)."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. (224) How are addressable detectors and modules assigned an address? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Device address is set when they are manufactured.",
            "b. By turning two rotary switches on the device.",
            "c. Setting \"dip\" switches on the device.",
            "d. Using manufacturer software."
        ],
        "correct": "b. By turning two rotary switches on the device."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. (225) What commercial code specifies or mandates maintenance requirements for fire protection systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 72.",
            "b. United Facilities Criteria (UFC) 3-601-02.",
            "c. NFPA 70.",
            "d. UFC 4-021-01."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 72."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. (225) How often are devices normally calibrated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Annually.",
            "b. Semi-annually.",
            "c. Every five years.",
            "d. Every two years."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Every five years."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. (226) Why do mass notification systems have priority over fire alarm systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Both systems function independently.",
            "b. Each condition is processed on a case by case basis.",
            "c. This is a false statement, fire alarm systems have priority.",
            "d. Perpetrators have been known to use the fire alarm system as a means of attack."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Perpetrators have been known to use the fire alarm system as a means of attack."
    },
    {
        "question": "71. (226) What color is the globe of a mass notification system (MNS) strobe in an Air Force facility? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Clear.",
            "b. Green.",
            "c. Red.",
            "d. Amber."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Amber."
    },
    {
        "question": "72. (226) What wattage is the maximum size of speaker used by an in-building mass notification system (MNS) without approval by the authority having jurisdiction (AHJ)? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 8 watts.",
            "b. 12 watts.",
            "c. 15 watts.",
            "d. 25 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 15 watts."
    },
    {
        "question": "1. (401) How many conductors must a clamp-on ammeter encircle to obtain an accurate current reading? ",
        "options": [
            "a. One.",
            "b. Two.",
            "c. Three.",
            "d. Four."
        ],
        "correct": "a. One."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (402) Which measurement determines the length of a screwdriver? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Overall length.",
            "b. Length of the tip.",
            "c. Length of the shank.",
            "d. Length of the blade."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Length of the shank."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (402) When using an adjustable wrench, why do you not apply a pulling force to the adjustable jaw?",
        "options": [
            "a. The wrench is likely to slip.",
            "b. You could break your wrist.",
            "c. The wrench is likely to bend.",
            "d. You could break your fingers."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The wrench is likely to slip."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (403) What tool should you use to cut openings when installing devices in finished walls? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Crosscut saw.",
            "b. Compass saw.",
            "c. Ripsaw.",
            "d. Jab saw."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Jab saw."
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (403) How is a hacksaw blade installed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Users preference.",
            "b. Teeth facing away from handle.",
            "c. Teeth facing towards the handle.",
            "d. Depends on material that is being cut."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Teeth facing away from handle."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (404) What conduit bender is normally used for Â½\" and Â¾\" EMT?",
        "options": [
            "a. Hickey bender.",
            "b. Electric bender.",
            "c. One-shot bender.",
            "d. Hydraulic bender."
        ],
        "correct": "c. One-shot bender."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (405) How do you know when a bit is properly tightened in a cordless drill? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Use a wrench to tighten the chuck.",
            "b. You tighten it Â½ turn past snug.",
            "c. You will hear a clicking sound.",
            "d. Until it doesn't move."
        ],
        "correct": "c. You will hear a clicking sound."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (406) What is the largest American standard wire gauge (AWG) size electrical wire? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/0.",
            "b. 2/0.",
            "c. 3/0.",
            "d. 4/0."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 4/0."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (406) The kcmil size range for conductors is ",
        "options": [
            "a. 100 to 1,000.",
            "b. 200 to 2,000.",
            "c. 250 to 2,000.",
            "d. 250 to 2,500."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 250 to 2,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (407) Pre-punched disks in a box that can be removed easily to permit conduit or cable connectors to be installed are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. blanks.",
            "b. pryouts.",
            "c. knockouts.",
            "d. connector disks."
        ],
        "correct": "c. knockouts."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (408) What is the purpose of a raised box cover? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Provides space for three additional devices.",
            "b. Allows for installation of a thicker wall surface after the box is mounted.",
            "c. Allows the box to be mounted five eighths of an inch behind the wall surface. d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box.",
            "d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (409) When you are connecting rigid conduit to boxes, what is/are required for circuits above 250 volts?  ",
        "options": [
            "a. One locknut and a bushing.",
            "b. Two locknuts and a bushing.",
            "c. Two bushings and a locknut.",
            "d. Two bushings and two locknuts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Two locknuts and a bushing."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (409) Which condition below is not allowed?  ",
        "options": [
            "a. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths less than 6 feet.",
            "b. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths greater than 6 feet.",
            "c. Using rigid metal conduit in lengths greater than 6 feet.",
            "d. Using liquid-tight flexible metal conduit in lengths greater than 6 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths greater than 6 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (410) Which ratings are always found on switches? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Volts and watts.",
            "b. Amperes and volts.",
            "c. Amperes and watts.",
            "d. Resistance and hertz."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Amperes and volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (411) What does the label TR signify on duplex receptacles? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Test regularly.",
            "b. Tamper resistant.",
            "c. Test resistor.",
            "d. Training regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Tamper resistant."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (412) Which part of a set of blueprints indicates the route of the service entrance? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Exterior elevations.",
            "b. Interior elevations.",
            "c. Detail drawings.",
            "d. Plot plan."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Plot plan."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (413) The simplest form of electrical diagrams is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. block diagram.",
            "b. wiring diagram.",
            "c. schematic diagram.",
            "d. connection diagram."
        ],
        "correct": "a. block diagram."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (414) The normal color code for wiring a device is ",
        "options": [
            "a. white to gold terminal, black to silver.",
            "b. black to gold terminal, red to silver.",
            "c. black to gold terminal, white to silver.",
            "d. red to gold terminal, black to silver."
        ],
        "correct": "c. black to gold terminal, white to silver."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (415) What is the general lighting load of an office building with 1,600 square feet of living area?",
        "options": [
            "a. 533 watts.",
            "b. 560 watts.",
            "c. 5,333 watts.",
            "d. 5,600 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5,600 watts."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (416) What is the total wattage of 9 ballasts rated at 1.5 amps each and fed by 277 volts? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1,350.",
            "b. 3,739.",
            "c. 4,155.",
            "d. 42,930."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 3,739."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (416) Heavy-duty lamp-holder outlets are calculated at ",
        "options": [
            "a. 300 volt-ohms.",
            "b. 300 volt-amperes.",
            "c. 600 volt-ohms.",
            "d. 600 volt-amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 600 volt-amperes."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (416) What is the required wattage for lighting of an industrial commercial (loft) building measuring 60 by 100 feet? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 6,000.",
            "b. 12,000.",
            "c. 18,000.",
            "d. 24,000."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 12,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (417) The code letter on a motor data plate identifies ",
        "options": [
            "a. the manufacturer's name.",
            "b. the voltage required for starting.",
            "c. the current required for starting.",
            "d. the locked-rotor current draw."
        ],
        "correct": "d. the locked-rotor current draw."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (418) To determine the total calculated load of a sub-panel, you should add all the amperages of the branch circuits plus what percent of the amperage of the largest motor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10.",
            "b. 15.",
            "c. 25.",
            "d. 30."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 25."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (419) How many current carrying conductors can be installed in raceway before the current capacity of the conductors must be de-rated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Three."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (419) All of the following are important when paralleling conductors, except what? ",
        "options": [
            "a. All conductors must be the same color.",
            "b. Phases and neutrals must be separated.",
            "c. Each neutral is run with its corresponding phases.",
            "d. All conductors must be of same material, size and length."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Phases and neutrals must be separated."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (420) How many conductors are required for a 3-phase-wye service entrance used for power and lighting? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Four ungrounded conductors.",
            "b. Three ungrounded conductors.",
            "c. Three ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors.",
            "d. Two ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Three ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (421) A transformer that has primary and secondary turns in a ratio of 1 to 10, respectively, is a ",
        "options": [
            "a. step-up transformer.",
            "b. power transformer.",
            "c. step-down transformer.",
            "d. distribution transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. step-up transformer."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (422) Power operated service disconnects are required to be designed so that they can be opened ",
        "options": [
            "a. externally.",
            "b. manually.",
            "c. quickly.",
            "d. slowly."
        ],
        "correct": "b. manually."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (423) Two ways to keep rain from entering service entrance (SE) cables are to use a weatherhead or ",
        "options": [
            "a. entrance ell.",
            "b. rain cap.",
            "c. gooseneck.",
            "d. junction box."
        ],
        "correct": "c. gooseneck."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (424) An underground distribution system is referred to as a service ",
        "options": [
            "a. entrance.",
            "b. feeder.",
            "c. lateral.",
            "d. burial."
        ],
        "correct": "c. lateral."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (424) Underground services installed with cable must be buried to a depth of at least ",
        "options": [
            "a. 18 inches.",
            "b. 24 inches.",
            "c. 30 inches.",
            "d. 36 inches."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 24 inches."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (425) In a panel with a neutral, what percentage is the smallest of the overcurrent devices that must be rated at 30 amperes or less for it to be classed as a lighting and appliance panel? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 5.",
            "b. 10.",
            "c. 20.",
            "d. 25."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 10."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (426) When installing a panelboard in a damp location, what number of inches is the minimum distance the cabinet must be placed from the wall? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/8.",
            "b. 1/4.",
            "c. 3/8.",
            "d. 1/2."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 1/4."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (426) The equipment ground bar and neutral bar are bonded together in a panel only when the panelboard also serves as the ",
        "options": [
            "a. distribution feeder.",
            "b. service lateral.",
            "c. load center.",
            "d. service entrance equipment."
        ],
        "correct": "d. service entrance equipment."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (426) The purpose of balancing the load on a panelboard is to  ",
        "options": [
            "a. reduce voltage drop.",
            "b. increase voltage drop.",
            "c. reduce total current flow. d. increase neutral current flow.",
            "d. increase neutral current flow."
        ],
        "correct": "a. reduce voltage drop."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (427) Which one of these circuits requires the use of GFCI protection? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bathrooms.",
            "b. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bedrooms.",
            "c. 240 V/50 A range circuit. d. 240 V/30 A dryer circuit.",
            "d. 240 V/30 A dryer circuit."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bathrooms."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (428) The conductors between the final overcurrent devices and the outlets for connecting electrical equipment are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. supply conductors.",
            "b. feeder conductors.",
            "c. distribution conductors.",
            "d. branch circuit conductors."
        ],
        "correct": "d. branch circuit conductors."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (429) What number is the CPS (Hertz) rating for most electrical equipment found in foreign countries? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 60.",
            "d. 400."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 50."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (430) What electrical component is the normal use of an octagonal box?",
        "options": [
            "a. Switches.",
            "b. Lighting outlet.",
            "c. Receptacle outlet.",
            "d. Special purpose receptacle."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Lighting outlet."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (431) What component must be equipped with a metal box used for an old-work installation? ",
        "options": [
            "a. F straps.",
            "b. Support ears.",
            "c. Spring metal clips.",
            "d. Self-tapping screws."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Support ears."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (432) What metallic cable has a #16 AWG aluminum bonding wire but does not have a green grounding conductor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. .Health care facility cable (HCF)",
            "b. Mineral insulated cable (MI).",
            "c. Metal clad cable (MC).",
            "d. Armored cable (AC)."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Armored cable (AC)."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (433) How is the minimum bend radius of metal clad cable calculated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Multiply the radius of the cable by 5.",
            "b. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 5.",
            "c. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 7.",
            "d. Multiply the radius of the cable by 7."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 7."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (434) A pigtail splice is finished with ",
        "options": [
            "a. plastic tape.",
            "b. a wire nut.",
            "c. epoxy resin.",
            "d. rubber and friction tape."
        ],
        "correct": "b. a wire nut."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (435) In addition to the splices required, grounding connections must be made to the boxes used in a circuit to ensure that they are ",
        "options": [
            "a. \"hot.\"",
            "b. \"cold.\"",
            "c. grounded.",
            "d. insulated."
        ],
        "correct": "c. grounded."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. (436) The maximum weight of a fixture that can be supported by an outlet box is",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 pounds.",
            "b. 20 pounds.",
            "c. 40 pounds.",
            "d. 50 pounds."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 50 pounds."
    },
    {
        "question": "47. (437) What is the taper per inch standard conduit-cutting die used on rigid metal conduit? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/4 inch.",
            "b. 1/2 inch.",
            "c. 3/4 inch.",
            "d. 1 inch."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3/4 inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "48. (438) Bends made to conduit while on the job are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. field bends.",
            "b. manual bends.",
            "c. working bends.",
            "d. handmade bends."
        ],
        "correct": "a. field bends."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. (439) When a number of conduit runs are to be installed parallel and adjacent to each other you should install the  ",
        "options": [
            "a. largest conduit first.",
            "b. smallest conduit first.",
            "c. smallest conduit on top. d. conduit all at the same time.",
            "d. conduit all at the same time."
        ],
        "correct": "d. conduit all at the same time."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. (439) Electrical metallic tubing (EMT) and IMC require supports within how many inches and feet of each outlet box, junction box, cabinet, or fitting, and every other foot thereafter. ",
        "options": [
            "a. 36 inches/10 feet.",
            "b. 18 inches/5feet.",
            "c. 12 inches/3 feet.",
            "d. 18 inches/5 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 36 inches/10 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. (440) The number of conductors you can put in conduit is based on the ",
        "options": [
            "a. size of conduit, conductor insulation, and length of run.",
            "b. size of conduit, conductor size, and conductor insulation.",
            "c. size of conductor, length of run, and number of bends.",
            "d. conductor insulation , length of run, and number of bends."
        ],
        "correct": "b. size of conduit, conductor size, and conductor insulation."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. (441) Which of these items is not a part of a direct current (DC) motor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Stator.",
            "b. Endbells.",
            "c. Armature.",
            "d. Brush assembly."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Stator."
    },
    {
        "question": "53. (442) The direct current (DC) shunt motor connects the field coils and armature in ",
        "options": [
            "a. series.",
            "b. parallel.",
            "c. series-parallel.",
            "d. parallel-series."
        ],
        "correct": "b. parallel."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (443) The component of a three-phase motor connected to the load is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. armature.",
            "b. endbell.",
            "c. rotor.",
            "d. stator."
        ],
        "correct": "c. rotor."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (444) The magnetic field of a three-phase motor rotor is caused by  ",
        "options": [
            "a. resistance in the squirrel cage.",
            "b. current flow in the rotor.",
            "c. impedance of the stator.",
            "d. voltage in the end bells."
        ],
        "correct": "b. current flow in the rotor."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. (445) Which of the following features describes three-phase motors best?",
        "options": [
            "a. Either single- or dual-voltage motors.",
            "b. Must be supplied by 220 volts.",
            "c. Always single-voltage motors.",
            "d. Always dual-voltage motors."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Either single- or dual-voltage motors."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. (446) The motor that requires some starting means is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. universal motor.",
            "b. direct current (DC) shunt motor.",
            "c. three-phase alternating current (AC) motor.",
            "d. single-phase AC motor."
        ],
        "correct": "d. single-phase AC motor."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. (447) Which of the following motors has the highest horsepower-to-weight ratio? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Direct current shunt motor.",
            "b. Universal motor.",
            "c. Three-phase dual-voltage motor.",
            "d. Single-phase capacitor start motor."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Universal motor."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. (448) A single-phase motor with external leads numbered T1, T2, T3, T4 is what type? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Single-voltage nonreversible.",
            "b. Single-voltage reversible.",
            "c. Dual-voltage nonreversible.",
            "d. Dual-voltage reversible."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Dual-voltage nonreversible."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. (449) Normally, an across-the-line motor control incorporates some type of ",
        "options": [
            "a. motor over-current protection.",
            "b. lightning protection.",
            "c. motor speed control.",
            "d. frequency control."
        ],
        "correct": "a. motor over-current protection."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. (450) The basic types of overload relays are ",
        "options": [
            "a. thermal and magnetic.",
            "b. single- and three-phase.",
            "c. mechanical and magnetic.",
            "d. undervoltage and overcurrent."
        ],
        "correct": "a. thermal and magnetic."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. (451) The methods used to open the contacts on an across-the-line magnetic controller are ",
        "options": [
            "a. spring tension and gravity.",
            "b. magnetic and thermal.",
            "c. thermal and hydraulic.",
            "d. metallic and magnetic."
        ],
        "correct": "a. spring tension and gravity."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. (451) A temperature-sensitive device to operate a magnetic across-the-line starter automatically is a ",
        "options": [
            "a. thermostat.",
            "b. float switch.",
            "c. pressure switch.",
            "d. photoelectric cell."
        ],
        "correct": "a. thermostat."
    },
    {
        "question": "64. (452) What are the three sections of a variable frequency drive? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Converter, alternating current (AC) Bus, and Inverter.",
            "b. Converter, direct current (DC) Bus, and Inverter.",
            "c. Pulse width modulation (PWM) Converter, DC Bus, and Inverter.",
            "d. Converter, Rectifier, and Inverter."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Converter, direct current (DC) Bus, and Inverter."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. (453) What type of bearing should be used in a vertically-mounted motor?",
        "options": [
            "a. Oillite sleeve.",
            "b. Bronze sleeve.",
            "c. Ball or roller.",
            "d. Phenolic and brass sleeve."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Ball or roller."
    },
    {
        "question": "66. (454) When you clean a motor with compressed air, what is the maximum air pressure to use? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 15 pounds per square inch (psi).",
            "b. 30 psi.",
            "c. 35 psi.",
            "d. 50 psi."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 30 psi."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. (455) If a motor has been operating normally but suddenly stops, you should suspect ",
        "options": [
            "a. improper connections.",
            "b. electrical overload.",
            "c. overvoltage.",
            "d. worn brushes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. electrical overload."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. (455) The end play of a motor should not exceed ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/8 of an inch.",
            "b. 1/16 of an inch.",
            "c. 1/32 of an inch.",
            "d. 1/64 of an inch."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 1/64 of an inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. (456) The conductor common to both the starting and holding circuits is connected to terminal ",
        "options": [
            "a. L1.",
            "b. T1.",
            "c. L2.",
            "d. T2."
        ],
        "correct": "a. L1."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. (457) A motor that operates slowly may have a ",
        "options": [
            "a. deficient voltage supply.",
            "b. ventilation problem.",
            "c. bad conductor.",
            "d. blown fuse."
        ],
        "correct": "a. deficient voltage supply."
    }
]